build Mastery over a specific Target and
you know become familiar with an
application at a I'm I almost just said
at an intimate level like me and this
application are like getting down and
dirty 9 pm
[Music]
all right dude we got some uh we got
some news today huh yeah yeah man
there's a there was a lot that went on
this week must be just beginning of the
month you know
yeah you want to take one or should I
yeah sure I mean I'll take the the first
the first big thing
um which is that yeah unfortunately uh
Port swiger creators of burp Suite they
have decided that they are going to be
ending their I think it was Weekly The
Weekly Newsletter uh the daily Swig
maybe it was daily I don't know yeah it
was called The Daily story but yeah yeah
I know it's sad to see that man I uh you
love to see quality content being put
out and aggregated in the bug Bounty
space in the cyber security space so sad
to see them go but yeah I definitely
definitely understand it is hard to keep
up with the pace of the industry for
sure 100 I mean I think if anything
we've learned that this is definitely a
full-time job at times yeah man yeah
yeah it definitely takes I mean even
just the aggregation of stuff like that
I feel like every time I'm looking
through Twitter I'm I'm you know on the
clock trying to aggregate some cool
stuff and luckily we had a nice little
planning session last week and we've got
some we've got some content planned out
a little bit so we were very organized
recently
but I could definitely see how trying to
do this every day
would uh definitely wear you down a
little bit
I was definitely a grind sad to see it
go but on on other news they have been
killing it poor Swagger has in the
research area do you see these three
links that I put in there about the um
the new access aspectors that they're
coming out with I did I did these are
really really awesome
um and I'm just thinking about a couple
different scenarios like literally in
the last week or two that uh xsses that
were like really really hard to exploit
that would have probably been a lot
easier to exploit
with these tips
yeah for sure man I I hadn't seen any of
this before and the one that kind of
blows my mind we'll link them down for
you guys in the description but
I'm specifically talking about the one
February 27th where uh he was taught he
has an a an a tag with an href the ahref
ref contains percent zero a and then
your JavaScript payload alert one yeah
and then when you click it it has an on
click as well and sets the protocol to
JavaScript
so then I guess so I guess what happens
here the order is the unclick triggers
sets the protocol of the href to
JavaScript and then when the href gets
triggered after the unclick finishes
then the protocol has already been
updated to JavaScript and then the
actual executed href is Javascript colon
percent OA alert one yeah yeah yeah it's
super super cool it's a super cool
attack Vector because I think all the
time you see like eight an a link that
you have more access to than you do like
an arbitrary element
um yeah and this is just a really great
attack Vector because it sort of puts
another spin on ways to sort of pop that
xss that are outside of the standard
vectors I I think I think I think this
one I think this one would probably be
most helpful if you've got like one of
those wafts that's kind of annoying
because
um you know obviously he's in inside the
unclick candelaer there's a protocol you
know piece being used
um you know so you're you're assigning a
variable already inside of on click so
you've already got JavaScript execution
um but the scenario where this would be
most helpful I think is payload
obfuscation to get past a WAFF and and
kind of do it a little bit more sneakily
in that in that way yeah for sure I know
that like a lot of apps are gonna block
on click maybe just by default but if
you have access to onclick and it's much
it's like a very sensitive laugh like
you like you mentioned that's probably a
great
um attack Vector where you basically set
this protocol to JavaScript and then
HTTP links uh from that page
are executed like JavaScript basically
yeah the one that that just blows my
mind is
um I don't I don't know how to tell you
which one it is I guess it's the one
that ends in seven zero six eight eight
um Joel in the dock it's it's the one
that that has a script tag and then
location dot protocol equals JavaScript
and then like inside the the script tag
there's like a comment
that has
oh no yeah no that's just the example
URL oh dude no way that's the example
URL yeah and so somebody actually on the
line on the earlier tweet that you we
were just talking about so yeah replied
and mentioned that oftentimes they see
that
um
there'll be a check that the eight that
the href location has to have either an
HTTP or an https on it but um if you put
two slashes at the end it works fine
yeah
no way so I think that's why in that in
that payload that you see you can see
it's like https Colton example.com then
you have your Advanced for payload and
then you end in two slashes yeah yeah so
then it updates the per the protocol
right and that's why the the percent OA
is necessary there it updates the
protocol wow okay this is sick guys you
definitely gotta go open up this this
payload I thought it was cool before I
understood it and now I understand it
this is nuts
um definitely check out this one this
tweet ending in 70688 in the description
from Portugal research because
essentially What's Happening Here is
it's reassigning the protocol and then
if I'm getting it correct Joel It's
commenting out from uh example all the
way to the new line and then it's
executing after that uh because that new
line bumps it down to the next line
inside the JavaScript and then it
executes alert one and comments out the
rest of it yes so I'm not sure like
whether or not like the comment has to
be within that script tag you know what
I mean I think that they're saying like
if you go to that URL no no no it's not
it's not that it's not that that URL
there but but you know know when it
updates the JavaScript protocol there
and it becomes JavaScript colon slash
right and then slash slash is a is a is
a comment in JavaScript so then it's
commenting out all the way into the
percent o a and then it's bumping down a
new line and then executing alert I
think is what's happening super
interesting they actually it's funny
people mentioned that they made a they
have a typo in their payload here they
did percentage and they tied it in with
alert but it needs to be presented zero
alert instead of percent zero alert yeah
so it's going to execute a function
called alert yeah yeah alert one alert
one you got like a like a hick hacker
there alert alert one and then I fired
the alert one alert one
and then the last one
that's right because I'm from Virginia
and I say yeah so I'm just making fun of
my own my own culture here
um yeah no so the last one was this uh
this research that they did
navigation.navigate and apparently
navigation is a uh is sort of a uh
experimental object within Chrome so
that's another method to get to get an
xss to pop if you have access to it yep
and again somebody in the comments uh on
the replies on this mentioned uh it it's
a little bit of an odd attack scenario
because you're basically executing
JavaScript from JavaScript but uh
portsmoker research replied and they
mentioned that it's basically just like
another uh like yeah another thing right
it's like your target
depending on what you're dealing with
depending on the page there's a lot of
different
scenarios that you're going to be
exporting some of them might end up
hitting navigate.navigate and if you
have a string that can lead into that
then you can pop an xss in a in another
different way which is uh yeah just
great knowledge to keep in the in the
back of your brain put it in your
notepad put in your sticky notes
yeah for sure I I appreciate uh ports
for your research is thoroughness here
because you know whenever we're writing
a tool or something like that they're
they're cheat sheet that they have is a
really good resource for knowing where
all of the sources and syncs are
um so yeah definitely shout out to them
for that yeah super super dope um Gareth
Gareth Hayes
um who wrote hack verder great burp
sweet plugin if you're not familiar with
it hack version is like I don't even
know how to describe it it's kind of
like the
decoder tool that's built into burp
Suite but on steroids so you can put in
little tags that basically automatically
encode and decode different types of
texts so helpful super great for you for
your research and your payload testing
you don't have to like encode something
send it change it encode it send it you
just type it in plain text and put it in
little tags that'll encode it the right
way and you're good to go one of the
things that I that I've noticed sort of
about this and this is just sort of a
general hacking principle is like if
you're trying to write an exploit for
something and you are just trying to get
the proof of concept you know in place
so prove to yourself that there's a
valid volume
um you gotta make that that
what is it like iteration cycle you know
the time it takes for you to try one
attempt you got to minimize that as much
as you possibly can because that just is
as as much friction as you can remove
from that as possible your brain is
spending less time thinking about okay
now I gotta encode this and I gotta
concode that and blah blah and it's
focusing more on okay this is the big
picture of the exploitation that's
happening and I think that's absolutely
pivotal so hackverter really does that
that well and allows you to kind of
without having to put too much thought
into it make sure that your payload's
getting encoded properly yeah clutch
yeah this is a it's taken me back to our
conversation about Automation and sort
of where you draw that line in terms of
this is something I should automate
versus this is something I should just
test manually and find the bug and
submit it yeah absolutely man since
we're on the topic of of Gareth Hayes I
figured I'd give a shout out here to his
JavaScript for hackers ebook
um yeah the guy just puts out constantly
amazing JavaScript uh payloads and
discoveries and research and I've only
read like the first chapter of the book
but in the first chapter you can just
tell how much he loves JavaScript he's
like man I just you know it's not about
the hacking for me it's just about
knowing everything about JavaScript I
just slapped my mic hopefully hopefully
that didn't get make two terrible sound
but he's just you know he's so
enthusiastic he's like I just want to
know every single thing about JavaScript
um and that's the kind of guy you want
writing a book called JavaScript for
hackers for sure so um definitely worth
every penny of 20 bucks that the book
costs and and yeah I mean the other
thing is that and this is sort of a rant
that I won't go too far down but
um
it's such a good it's such a good and
such an important practice to invest in
yourself as a professional in any
industry and even more so in the cyber
security industry so getting educational
materials like this book getting certs
that are going to add value like the
oscp and offensive security products
um that is that is absolutely worth
every penny you put into it so um
definitely go ahead and pick up this
book by Gareth Hayes yeah absolutely I
think it's one of those sort of
you you know you might read like the
whole book and only pull like a couple
like key really useful things but those
key useful things are going to be really
really useful and they're going to be
super useful down the line you're gonna
like pull on that knowledge constantly
um yeah and it might not even be
immediately apparent as you're reading
it like ah this is something that's
super useful but I'm I'm almost certain
that as you're hacking you're gonna pick
up on some things and you're gonna be
like oh I read it it's almost like it's
almost like the butterfly effect you
know inside of hacking inside of
knowledge is just kind of getting that
knowledge knowing how all these various
pieces work together you start to be
able to craft a better picture of how
the JavaScript engines working and how
all the different pieces fit together
um and so definitely yeah definitely has
a lot of value yeah he also mentions in
the description that uh there is he he
covers this thing called JS [__] uh
which is something that I have messed
around with quite a bit but essentially
it's building JavaScript payloads using
only Plus open and close square bracket
open and close parentheses and the
exclamation symbol so just that yeah
that set of what two four six characters
it's nuts it's it's super super cool if
you want to dig into it to see how it
actually works you you definitely can
but I I totally recommend buy this have
you have you like I still have no idea
how that works do you have any remotest
idea how that works or have you just
kind of played with it yeah so it's
essentially if you if you think about
like have JavaScript implicitly converts
things if you have like two two
parentheses uh like that's like calling
something that yeah will evaluate to a
like a string called function yeah okay
and from there you have indexes so if
you do like a string function index zero
that's the letter F kidding and so you
can build out an entire alphabet that is
based on that or you can do offsets from
care codes and yeah it's it's absolutely
do you have to get to an eval statement
or something or uh no because you can
run it as a function so it's
at a certain point you could just return
stuff essentially
oh my gosh dude that's crazy man yeah I
I definitely want to go in after this
and kind of suss out exactly how it kind
of gets to works out all the different
pieces because that's that's crazy I
have used it before though actually in
like an actual exploitation context
there's just a really tight laugh and I
knew I was in the the JavaScript context
so I was just like boom I'm just gonna
I'm just gonna encode it with this and
and there you go yeah all about WAFF
bypasses today
yeah man I don't know I I to be honest I
haven't really come up against a WAFF in
a while
um most of the excesses that I've I've
kind of been popping lately have yeah I
mean most are on the main application
and you're not really sticking a WAFF in
front of the main application a lot of
times so
yeah I know exactly what you mean um I
have seen a couple recently and usually
it's not like a homegrown laugh
um yeah but there are definitely still
laughs out there I think it's starting
to consolidate into just a couple
mainstream ones where they just don't
use a laugh at all and they just do
sanitization on their inputs and call
today
yeah yeah well I mean it's the better
way I feel like I feel like a WAFF is a
little bit of a safety net
um but yeah it definitely takes
performance off of your application so
you know if you're talking about some of
these bigger bigger targets that need
performance as as a part of their
business use case it's not super super
feasible to do that 100 all right what
else we got in here we're gonna talk
about uh rojans oh yeah yeah so for
those who don't know rojin AKA uranium
238 uh he's pretty old school hacker I
actually work with him and he started a
company called uh ophion ofion I'm not
sure I pronounce it but uh o5 security
he's been doing a lot of really awesome
security research and work through that
company
including I think there's a B-side star
coming up pretty soon he's gonna be
given about
um
I think about GitHub stuff but he did a
blog post recently about finding code
space uh secrets on GitHub through I
believe through the import feature which
I don't know if we talked about this
last week but I know there was another
bug uh on GitHub yeah that was an
exercise popped through uh a repo import
yeah actually I think this one is is a
is a security advisory is kind of how he
pops it oh is there yeah yeah and then I
think you might be confusing it with one
of the other ones hopefully we don't
have to bleep out any of that hopefully
he's fine with us talking about other
other work he's done but
um yeah this one's a a temporary fork
and I'm actually a little bit salty at
him because like I I looked at this
target at a live hacking event like
earlier last year and uh and I missed
this and not only did he find this but
he also escalated it by hitting a GitHub
actual an actual GitHub repo and an
organization repo which is yeah such
yeah that's what it was yeah and that's
just so big brain like he he takes this
and then applies it straight to GitHub
and ends up being able to pull a token
for the user GH containers Dash Bots
which has a bunch of like read write
access to internal repositories and
stuff like that so super cool that's
that's pretty sick and I will say for
any of you that are interested in GitHub
as a Target
um code spaces is a super fascinating
Target I I I I didn't love hacking on
GitHub before this past life hacking
event that we did with them
um but they they sort of you know nudged
us a little bit towards code spaces
during that event and I was so glad they
did because it's such a cool it's such a
cool
um feature and there's a lot of scope in
there without going too much into detail
about about the Vols uh there's a lot of
scope in there where you can you know do
funky stuff especially and this is
another thing I wanted to shout out the
podcast about GitHub
um if anyone's just hacking any GitHub
related products
um there's one concept that results in
so many volumes that GitHub cannot do
um they cannot get rid of it for legacy
reasons if you Fork a repo
and you commit to the forked copy of the
repo
then that commit hash
can be accessed on the original repos
tree
and that just results in so many
vulnerabilities because you know anytime
they're trying to do repository level
access controls you can fork and then
your malicious you know Fork your
malicious commit that you've you've
pushed to your fork that that can be
accessed
um via a commit hash in the original
um repository so I know I've talked to
their security team a little bit they're
doing their best to kind of keep those
volumes to a minimum but it's definitely
a cool trick that you need if you're
going to go hack get up products that's
a super interesting attack scenario so
basically if you say you you find a bug
that's referencing an arbitrary commit
hash you can Fork it make some changes
provide your own commit hash that's from
your fork and it would work
well it's I'm I it's not exactly like
that so what what it is is it's when for
example there's you need to have
specific content in a repo right so
let's say like you own a repo Joel right
and I don't have right access to that
repo I've only got read access right but
I do have the ability to Fork so I fork
your repo right and I commit into my own
repo
then I get the commit hash from that and
I can craft a URL that starts with Slash
Joe Margolis vulnerable repo slash my
commit hash and it will show my commits
content in your repo because my my uh my
repo is a fork of yours so it's it's a
it's a real weird little little trick
that you can do that's just a part of
that sort of deeper get stuff that I
don't understand but
um Tom mentioned that to me once before
and then I want to say the other guy's
name was not an aardvark
um I'll have to go see if I can look it
up but he's kind of a prolific GitHub
hacker so
um talk to him about that as well yeah
GitHub has a huge attack surface I I
remember I I hacked on them a couple
years ago and I found a pretty cool
um interesting bug that was within one
of their pre-release features
so a lot of times they gate their
pre-release features with these specific
headers that you have to send yeah and
otherwise like if you hit the end point
it doesn't work at all
and I thought that was a great attack
surface because it would be stuff that
most people probably haven't tested or
looked at and sure enough I was able to
find a really cool bug in there I don't
actually know if it's uh resolved yet
but I'll have to look it up and see
maybe we can talk about it yeah for sure
definitely definitely let me know about
that that sounds like a good one for the
for the reports section and I'm excited
for the report section today
um we're gonna have two of the guys that
I mentee come on and kind of talk about
their reports I that are my mentees that
I Mentor uh are come on and talk about
some of some cool reports that they've
found
um so should be cool to see what kind of
stuff they come up with yeah I saw the
in the docks so I'm pretty I'm pretty
pumped to hear about what they found and
and hear about the whole experience
they're good bugs one of the guys right
now is is working on a bug that's like
just phenomenal and I think he's I think
we've we've got it to the point where
it's gonna be it's like for sure it's
just gonna take a crap ton of
programming but the exploit is going to
be like probably 300 400 lines of code
long so it's gonna be it's gonna be a
big one for sure that's awesome
cool uh all right on to the next let's
see yeah uh we got rezo's tweet and we
got the live hacking standards which one
do you want to go Let's do let's do the
live hacking event standards okay cool
um yeah so I I just popped this on here
because
um one of the things that the community
has been talking about for a little
while is hacker one's uh impact
requirements for the life hacking event
standards
um you know they were saying that you
need to have I want to say it was like a
23 or 22 impact or above to get invited
to the life hacking events and um and
that was getting a lot of backlash
because it's like okay well do you
literally just not want us to report
lows and mediums in order to you know
get invited to the live hacking events
and I don't think that's what hacker one
wants and you know talk to them about
that but to be perfectly honest man I'm
a little bit
uh I'm a little bit on the fence about
their their fix to this so go click on
the link that I put in the dock and then
if you scroll down
um it's the one that says hacker one per
uh platform performers in the last 180
days right and it still says researchers
with more than 75 percent of submitted
reports being hire critical
so I guess that could be I mean that
wouldn't be
22 impact like if you submitted a bunch
of you know 75 of your bugs are
are you know highs then you're at 25.
and then you know you've got maybe like
a bunch of lows and that would pull you
down into like the 20 range and then but
still 75 of your bugs being higher
critical seems a little bit a little bit
I mean 75 of my bugs aren't higher
critical yeah I don't think mine are
either um yeah you know look I
definitely sympathize with hacker one on
this I think yeah
they've been put in a tricky situation
because in the early days of live
hacking events it was very much so an
organic sort of natural process where
they basically just wanted to invite top
hackers whatever that sort of means it's
basically just people who perform well
at events
um who are consistent about finding
really good bugs who can provide high
impact and high value to the customers
that doesn't mean that you find 100
criticals 100 highs all the time just
means that that's sort of your skill set
and that's not exactly an easy skill set
to pinpoint the problem is that over
time over the years the more events that
they did the more publicity that they
got the more that they advertised and
talked about the events the more people
that wanted to come to the events right
um and so unfortunately they got into
this situation where they have to
explicitly Define how people get invited
right because now if somebody doesn't
get an invite they go well why didn't I
get an invite wow yeah they need some
sort of hard reason to explain why you
did or didn't get an invite and that's
very difficult to do and I think they
tried to structure a lot of these rules
around sort of like to get a mimic of
what they've been inviting already but
you know if you write stuff like this
it's you're gonna back yourself into a
corner where now you have to invite
these people you can't invite these
people
um yeah and I've seen personally as well
as with friends of mine who are really
really good hackers who have been to
tons of live hacking events who just
don't get an invite because they don't
meet the criteria anymore and yeah it's
uh it's kind of unfortunate it's a
tricky situation for hacker one because
I think it's good to standardize it but
it's also good to sort of keep that
natural aspect to the hacking events so
they have they have a little bit of a
they're they're in a bit of a corner
yeah yeah I totally agree and and you
know
it's difficult you know I think too but
I I think what they need to kind of sit
down and decide is what does the ideal
hacker look like you know for this
specific for this specific category
right because I think that's what
they're trying to say like what it what
does the ideal hacker look like on our
platform and for me I don't think that's
a hacker with 75 of their bugs being
higher critical because I mean at the
end of the day I don't think you can do
that without not reporting some lows and
mediums and and to be honest um you know
along the way you know you're we're all
looking for highs and criticals that's
the goal for sure but along the way you
you hit some lows and you hit some
mediums and they're not always going to
be chainable sometimes they are and
that's great but
um sometimes you've just got a bug this
is this is never going to be chained but
it needs to be fixed and and you know
there's some risk associated with it so
I don't know man I I would still like I
would I feel like maybe this Criterion
is a little bit
um disconnected from what the actual
hacking process looks like and what it
looks like to build Mastery over a
specific Target and uh you know become
familiar with an application at a I'm I
almost just said it at an intimate level
like me and this application are like
getting down and dirty yeah
[Laughter]
um but yeah no uh I I think you know
getting intimate with the application
you know understanding the the ins and
outs of it some lows and mediums are
gonna are gonna pop up for sure so
um yeah it's an improvement for sure but
in my opinion it's not quite there still
but all the other categories look really
good I know that there's going to be
some some uh just sort of new to live
hacking events section where they talk
about uh criticality consistency and
Community those are the three C's that
determine the mvh for the life hacking
events
um and so you know people that have
demonstrated that within the community
will earn themselves up to five
researchers an invite to the event and
then also um I also like to see up to 10
research from uh geolocation based
selection so wherever the live hacking
event is if it's local to you you'll
have a chance of getting an invite from
just from that
um and I think that's pretty cool yeah I
think I think it's awesome to
incorporate the local hackers and stuff
a lot of these communities and the
locations have really awesome local
hacker communities and local hacker
groups and just local hackers in general
that are undiscovered or you know
underappreciated talent and this is a
great opportunity to sort of shine some
light on that but you know again that it
opens the opportunity for a new person
to get invited and then be immediately
excluded from the next one because they
don't meet the criteria right so yeah I
think that there is some room for
refinement but overall it's great to see
them being uh so public about this and
making adjustments to the rules I know
that they've had these rules for quite a
number of years yeah but I think this is
maybe the first blog post I've seen
about it I think it's mostly just been
in PDF form
um yeah
but yeah I think
something that you mentioned and we'll
probably talk more about this is sort of
the you're not always going to submit
highs and crits and our later discussion
is going to be about full-time bug bunny
hacking and I'm sure that somebody who
acts full-time doesn't only submit highs
and crits right so heck yeah man let's
let's let's hop on to that after we talk
about rezzo real quick because I wanted
to he he put out this treat and I really
like rezzo's tweets a lot of the time
and I think he he adds a lot of value
um but there's one that I just kind of
had to
throw a hot takeout on
um number two so I'll link it in the in
the description but he says uh book
Bounty is a lot of luck but you control
how many times you roll the dice here's
five ways to maximize your luck of
finding a bug and he talks about number
one fuzzing all the things that's great
I agree with that number two don't
Rabbit Hole so I'm just going to read
this outward for it because it's pretty
short don't spend more than a few
minutes on any one thing until you
finish the app uh Arch Archangel uh
Douglas does this extremely well the
first time I saw him hacking I was
shocked at how fast he was testing the
app now
yeah I I don't know man what do you
think I I won't shoot my my opinion out
there first I want to get yours yours
and hear what you think well it's
interesting because this was also
something that I put on my question
sheet to ask you about full-time hacking
but oh really cool I feel
it's really hard to Define this in like
a hard set rule
um because there are lots of times we'll
be hacking on a Target and you'll feel
like this is not something that's worth
pursuing
but I should keep hacking on it and keep
poking at it because I think that there
might be something further here
versus I need to optimize the amount of
time that I'm hacking on this so let me
just move on and look at all the other
features because I'm hacking on a big
application right yeah
yeah I think I think there is a balance
I will say I'm not going to come in too
hot here but I will say that I firmly
disagree with this I think
um I think one of the ways one of the
things that changed about me
um about the way I hacked uh starting I
guess maybe 2021
um was I hacked more in the in the past
I focused more on like really trying to
find everything and like getting all
this coverage and like really you know
to be fairly honest I was it was before
I had won an MBH and I was shooting for
the MBH you know I wanted to kill
everything find all the bugs you know
and dominate the event right but when I
stopped having that mentality I actually
won my mbhs
um and the reason for that was because I
was Finding bugs that were more
interesting that were deeper in the
application and that were more impactful
and um and I've mentioned this in the
past this is one of my one of my tips
for for Life hacking events is you don't
we have two weeks you know three weeks
maybe two to to attack these giant
companies with these big Scopes you're
not going to be able to cover everything
so don't even try if you're on a team
maybe you could you know split stuff up
and somebody could you know go wide and
you know an inch deep but at the end of
the day to find the best bugs you're
going to need to go deep and so I say
rabbit hole as much as you can try to
find try to find those those weird parts
of the application that you can become a
super expert on and make sure that those
those parts of the applications are very
close to what the business values
because then once you become more
intimately familiar here I am again me
and me and this application are getting
it on man you know once you become more
more intimately acquainted with the uh
with the application you'll be able to
see you know you'll find more impactful
bugs that are and they'll also be a lot
of in my experience they'll also be a
lot of them
um and so it's not necessarily that
you're gonna all you're gonna you're
gonna be you know that person that
submits one super crit and is like super
proud of it and and that person's great
and you know that's definitely a valid
strategy but I think um you know rabbit
holding finding something very close to
the business
um data or the business value and then
becoming a Super expert on that is a
better way to go in my opinion yeah and
I think you see this success story over
and over again where like you'll go to a
hack a program for example you look at
the leaderboard and it's like the rep is
like 150 180 200 250
2500. and yeah exactly what like what
what happened between number two and
number one right and it's that number
one has been hacking on this and going
deep right like they've been going in
they've been taking lots of notes
they've been finding all the little
nuances they've been exploring the edge
cases and the fringes of the application
that nobody else has been looking at and
that's why the 2000 repire yeah yeah for
sure and that you know that person
definitely isn't the person that just
went you know an inch deep in a mile
wide on the application
um and and to be fair in the context of
live hacking events I think you also
have to do the trade-off of like okay
well I'm only going to be looking at
this target for three weeks can I really
become an expert on this in three weeks
um and you know that's gonna be a know
yourself sort of situation there but
um for me I I've just been starting to
hit those deadlines man where like you
know right as we're as the event is
getting close I'm like you know popping
out some really good bugs the day before
the event or even the day of the event
because my my knowledge of the
application is starting to solidify and
I'm really starting to get it it's
starting to click so yeah yeah and I
think live hacking events are kind of a
little bit of an edge case because you
have such that finite timeline and not
only that you're racing against other
like top Elite hackers right so
everybody has the same scope some people
might be more familiar than others but
usually you kind of hope that it's a
scope that nobody has seen yet and
you're all on sort of a Level Playing
Field which also means that everybody's
like racing to be the best starting from
the same place right it's like a you're
on a track right everybody's at the
starting line who's gonna make it to the
end the first who's gonna have the best
you know whatever and you have to really
balance that like
how much time am I going to spend on
this versus moving on how much time has
somebody else spent on this somebody
already found this bug is there a bug
here that I haven't found yet that I'm
going to spend all day finding that
maybe somebody else has found so I think
there's a lot
a lot more involved in that decision
lifespan yeah versus if you're just
picking any Target you know any public
program any private program you have a
generally a pretty good idea that
there's not going to be like that same
caliber of people focusing on it to the
same level for the same period of time
and if you take your time and you
develop that familiar familiarity that
intimacy as you call it with the program
then you'll be able to get a little bit
further than everybody else because
they're focusing on other programs yeah
yeah for sure man yeah and and I just
want to clarify you know I really
appreciate rezo's tweets and you know
sharing knowledge and stuff like that
and and you know one way or the other uh
we're generating content we're
generating controversy so we're we're
figuring out how to do this thing better
together
um and just just a once over the other
five things that he pointed out here so
he says fuzz all the things you know
fuzz V host fuzz headers fuzz parameters
fuzz everything and I definitely think
that is one way of going about it I've
seen a lot of people successful with
that I don't know that I have
um you know really mastered that I think
that I've got a lot of improvement to do
in that area and I think rezo probably
does that a decent bit better than me
um number three so we're skipping number
two because I don't you know not going
to show up
um uh uh number three dedicate time each
day I totally agree with this you know I
yeah it sometimes it's just it's just I
mean this is I think this is the the
most correlatory thing to his original
tweet at the beginning that says hey you
control how many times you roll the dice
like if you're getting in there and
you're putting in the hours you are 100
gonna find a bug it's just gonna take a
lot of time and it's not and uh and I
think a lot of people this is one thing
I've been kind of talking about with my
mentees lately too I think a lot of
people sort of fade out before before
they should on these sort of things yeah
um yeah so share your leads uh you know
hit up your local Joel and uh and say
Joel please help me with this lead
um and then invest time into learning
new attacks I don't know what do you
think about that last one Joel I mean I
think that's definitely true and I've
seen deaf program sort of kill it with
the request muddling stuff
um but yeah there are a lot of bugs out
there that are you know older that are
still all over the place yeah I mean
listen if you're listening to this
podcast you're already
sort of you know you're there a little
bit right like you're you're investing
in new attacks you're learning you're
exploring you're trying to consume sort
of what's going on and stay up to date I
think you see this so often where any
any industry it doesn't have to be Tech
doesn't have to be bug bounty
anybody who falls behind and just stays
stagnant and doesn't keep learning and
stay on the front edge you're gonna be
that Professor who's talking about like
you know
instead of doing it you know I invented
TCP it's like cool man but like what
about like everything else
I invent the TCP dang dude that that I
feel like that's one of my professors at
college man there's just everybody's had
it like at least one of those professors
that's like yeah you know back back when
I was in school you know we were
inventing the internet and it's like oh
wow just come out and I was scared and
then they give you a homework assignment
that's like some like old Antiquated
like not relevant write this in Cobalt
yeah you know like
no um the one thing that he does say in
here is Cash deception have you played
around with cash deception much I I have
found a lot of cash deception bones and
I always look for it I think it's
because of Andre's influence but I found
out recently that not a lot of people
are looking for that is that yeah what
do you think yeah I mean caching is a
huge it's a huge problem it leaves so
much room for problems just in every
application I think there was a Twitter
thread just today about Loom uh Loom is
some like I don't know I don't really do
but they mentioned that they were
experiencing a problem where some users
were being logged into other users
accounts and like you're just like open
Loom and you would be in someone else's
account and dang dude I can almost
guarantee this is a caching problem
because yeah I I use Loom I I actually
tried to log into my account yesterday
and it was broken so I'm hoping nobody's
logged into my account right now that's
kind of crazy there you go so I'm sure
their security incident response team is
going crazy right now trying to figure
out who accessed what and all that kind
of stuff but
caching is one of those things that
makes an application work way better and
way faster and be just better as a whole
but it also leaves a lot of risk for you
to mess something up and I think it's
one of those things that flies so
underneath the radar that you might just
like skip over the header right you see
like a cash control header or something
and you're like God that's just you know
delete that that's part of the normal
response whatever move on and actually
learning how cache control works and how
cash Inception works and request
smuggling and the actual like details
and fine details behind it you know it's
one of those investing times into time
into learning new attacks at some point
it's probably a good idea to just sit
down and
Focus spend some Focus time spend a day
spend a couple hours and just play
around with it in a controlled
environment so you get to get a real
good understanding for how something's
working and then you can take it out
into the real world
yeah for sure I just noted it down maybe
we'll do an episode on webcast reception
and
um uh web cache poisoning those are both
really interesting vulnerability types
and and I think are sort of under under
researched so we'll put that on the put
that on the Queue cool all right you
want to talk about full-time bug bunny
hacking let's do it man you got some you
got some questions here for me well we
do uh hit me okay cool um well let's
just start with like maybe you can tell
me a little bit about what your
day-to-day looks like because at least
for me I'll give some context like I'm a
security engineer so I work
nine to five equivalent you know eight
hours a day I start working I finish
work and then I'm done with work so I'd
be curious to hear sort of like what
does your day-to-day look like do you
work eight hours a day do you work two
hours a day do you work weekends you
know I'd love to hear
yeah um so
good question uh yeah I I I'd say it
varies a lot um during the life hacking
events um which happen every couple
months
um
I I'm hitting it pretty hard I'd say
probably my minimum is eight
um mostly looking more like a 10 or a 12
hour day during those events just kind
of grinding it out and um you know the
bounties are higher the uh you know
incentives are there the bonuses are
good so it's a good time to really like
hit it hard
um outside of that uh normally after the
live hacking events I take some time off
so normally that's a week or two
um I'd say maybe total of like I
probably work maybe 10 months a year
um maybe a little bit less
um and obviously that's not paid time
off
um because I'm you know bugs equal money
for me
um and so I
have I can pay myself from my LLC
and then you know I can sort of have
paid time off uh but it you know I'm not
I'm not actually making any money during
that time which is a little bit tricky
um so yeah that that's and then I'd say
like the average day-to-day
um I I probably work uh maybe like six
six to eight um when I'm not in the uh
live hacking event so six to eight hours
not not six o'clock to eight pm yeah
just a casual you know 14 hours
14-hour day no biggie yeah as you do
um so you mentioned that like especially
during Live Hack events you're really on
the grind you're really like pushing
into it do you take breaks do you
control your time in like a meaningful
purposeful way at all or do you sort of
just
flow with energy level or yeah I kind of
flow with the energy levels man
um I I'm not a big break taker uh it
interrupts my focus I even get irritated
when I have to get up and go to the
bathroom I'm like all right let me just
like finish this thing before I go
um yeah uh so no I I it's pretty much
like a it's almost always a full
10 hours like streak and Mariah is
amazing we've kind of built out for
those of you that don't memorize my wife
and during the live hacking events we've
kind of hit a system where she
understands that I'm going to be very
busy and she also understands that you
know during the day even though I'm not
you know going to grab lunch with her
like I normally do or something like
that during a regular work day
um that when I'm not working I will be
entirely present with her and with the
other activities around but during the
day I'm totally focused so she brings me
food I don't even realize I'm eating it
half the time uh you know she just plops
it down and then I eat it and I just
move along very focused don't take a lot
of breaks and and but I know other
people do I want to say today's new Eric
you know does a break every like 30
minutes or something like that he'll get
up and walk around so it's there's
definitely different strategies to it
cool yeah no that's uh that's something
that I definitely I mean especially
during the work day I tend to sit down
and just I work like just until I have
no energy left so yeah that's that's
something I can definitely relate with
um you mentioned that like you know bugs
equals income right and um I think
that's probably the biggest hurdle for a
lot of people who consider doing bug
money full-time is that you don't have
that sort of stability there's no
guaranteed income it's all basically
what you put in is what you get out and
even that is sometimes you could put in
so much and just get nothing out right
yeah exactly yeah um so how do you like
how do you manage your time and trying
to optimize sort of your income so like
how do you picture to hack on when do
you choose to
call it and move on and go to the next
Target or
um sort of what we talked about like
when do you decide that something's not
worth going any deeper into and move on
to the next part of the application Yeah
Yeah It's Tricky man for sure I think um
I think you know what I'm focusing on is
largely determined by the life hacking
event so if I'm in a live hacking event
then I'm you know focusing on the target
obviously and when I'm not in a live
hacking event I
have a couple well for one I prioritize
the hacker one challenges that come up
because those are fresh targets
the bounties are normally like pretty
decent
um and so I'll go after those I hit one
of those recently but when there's no
hacker one challenges and there's no
life hacking event then I'm going after
my uh uh you know Old Reliable program
um I've I've kind of landed on that
being instacart
um finally get to shout them out on here
nice
um the great bounties
um awesome team very responsive uh yeah
I just really enjoyed working with them
so I hit them pretty hard
um and yeah when do I say what do I call
it when do I move on most of the time my
attention is forcibly diverted
um for Life hacking event so if I'm if
I'm in the middle of hacking on
instacart and I'm in deep and I'm you
know in a certain section of the
application even if an H1 challenge
comes up I I won't necessarily jump on
it I'll stick with it and then I'll
continue hacking that Target until the
live hacking event comes up
um the the hacker One World Cup is
coming up which I think I will will
prioritize over my other stuff which it
did take some thought because
there are going to be I think the dupe
situation is a little bit challenging
there because there's not they're not
doing a due period so it's just going to
be a lot of people hacking on a Target
but I've decided I'm gonna go
um you know for a little bit more
obscure vulnerabilities some some
Specialties of mine that I feel like
most other people won't be able to find
and hopefully that will that will pay
off pretty well
um regarding your note on you know the
stability piece I don't I don't think
that I
this is one of the things that I'm most
grateful for in the world I I don't know
that I would have ever pulled the
trigger on going full time Buck Bounty
if Mariah hadn't
pretty much insisted that I do it
um because like I don't know I really do
I'm someone that really naturally values
that stability and so
um
you know you definitely want to have
some Runway you definitely want to have
uh I would say you know at least six
months to a year of runway in your in
your bank before you um kick off
somebody I know who's about to go
full-time Buck Bounty is aiming for two
years Runway which I think is a little a
little excessive but I told I told them
that and they're like you know hey it is
what it is yeah yeah for sure and I
totally get that
um but yeah I don't know that I would
have ever done it but Mariah said dude
you know you're making more money
hacking part-time than you are at your
main job full time so this doesn't make
any sense
um and then yeah so at that point we've
kind of pulled the trigger and at that
time uh when I switched to full-time bug
Bounty I was moving to Japan so the
healthcare problem was sort of solved by
being a student at a language School in
Japan and getting Health Care through
the government there
um and yeah it's kind of worked like
like that ever since so I'm curious
why maybe you could give me some
background about what made you choose to
do the switch instead of if you're
already making more than you're making
at your full-time job why not keep the
full-time job as just passive stable
income and then make the majority of
your income on the side doing you know
basically a hobby
yeah now that's a great question and I
think I I um I've actually advised a
couple of my friends that are like hey
should I go full-time bug Bounty
um to keep their their full-time jobs
especially if it's Kush you know there
are some security gigs that are just
chill-af out there you know they really
are and they pay they do not pay a
nominal amount of money
um I was not I was not making super much
I was making 70 bass when I when I came
out of college
um and uh and so you know there are some
people over on on the west coast you
know in the mid you know in the 200
range and I'm like I wouldn't leave that
job if I were you you know
um and so uh yeah I I think it's
relative and for me
um when I was hacking part-time it was
taking a lot of it was taking all of my
free time and it was you know putting it
into this money making hobby which was
great and I and I and I enjoyed the
hobby
um but also I wanted to be able to do
other things with my free time as well
and you know just more things with my
time than just security so shifting bug
bounty to my main income allowed me to
still kill it in Buck Bounty have fun
and um you know participate in that
Community while also being able to you
know I just went and played pickleball
for a couple hours right before we
started this podcast and I do a podcast
and you spend time with my wife and
friends so that's kind of that's kind of
the main goal to get time back yeah so
about speaking about like the time stuff
I know we talked a little bit about how
much you work each day and all that kind
of stuff outside of live hacking events
do you hack on weekends is it weekdays
only
um it depends so you know because I'm
not limited to a traditional schedule
sometimes I'll you know my weekend will
be Tuesday Wednesday Thursday and you
know we'll go do a trip or something
like that when no one else is around and
you know while the the lines are short
or the you know the crowds aren't there
which is great and then in those
scenarios I will work on weekends
sometimes but um I definitely try to
avoid working on Sunday that's sort of a
a um a Christian principle and I think
it's really wise whether you're a
Christian or not is uh is just having
one day set aside for rest that's just
like holy to you you know this is like
you don't infringe upon that because
um
at least for me I I'm definitely stray
more on the side of like I want to work
more I want to work I want to work I
want to push it push it push it right
and so having one day that's just kind
of like no this day is a day where we
sit on our couch and read a book or we
sit in the hot tub and you know chill
versus hacking I think that's been a big
value for me got it so if you're taking
time off
um it's a little bit of a complicated
relationship because you are both the
employee and the employer right yeah
everything is relying on you and I had a
lot of this struggle when I was in
college but essentially doing bug Bounty
full-time where I got to a point where I
I felt like I was being
like a very aggressive boss towards
myself essentially where I was like I
have to be working I have to be right
and how do you balance that where you
get to take time off but you don't want
to feel bad about taking time off
well I've got this great boss Mariah who
uh says who's very much like dude if I'm
a workaholic she is like just so able to
if I'm being a workaholic she is so able
to just shut that down and like slap me
out of it and just be like dude what are
you doing like no we're about to go take
a trip and like it's gonna be a blast
this is this is you know
this is why we made this decision and so
um I definitely struggle with that I
definitely struggle with being like I
gotta get back to work I gotta I gotta
work but then she just reminds me you
know like no you don't and you can come
and chill and do this and uh you know
I've been doing it for
just actually it's three years this
month
um that I've been full-time Buck Bounty
um and uh yeah I'm just kind of now
getting the swing of like being able to
pretty guilt-free be like yeah okay you
know what I'm off you know and that's
how it is and and I'll pick up the slack
a different day or I'll ride on the
slack of uh provided by you know the
last live hat came out or whatever got
it do you um do you ever feel like you
get burned out or overworked doing it
full time
yeah yeah I mean it's definitely a
danger
um I kind of talked a little bit about
this um in the in a panel with hacker
one um a while back but
um for me
oh burnout and overwork comes from when
I it mostly comes from when I try to put
my identity in my work and then I I
don't fulfill it so if I am aiming for
one you know number one for mvh at a
live hacking event and then I get like
12th or like 20th or something like
in those scenarios that's when I feel
like you know what I just I'm burnt out
on this like I tried my best and I can't
you know do anything
um
and so for me you know having shifted my
and I did that for a long time and there
was a period when I strongly considered
quitting bug Bounty
um right after I had first go started
going full time
um but then I you know I realized hey
you know my my self-worth is found in
other things besides my work performance
uh for me it's it's found in the love of
Jesus for others that have done it
successfully it's it's found in
relationships it's found in you know
living their best life that they can and
and to each their own
um but uh yeah I think if you've got
your you know your identity you're not
putting your identity in your work and
you're you're setting reasonable
boundaries obviously you know you can't
be doing three months of 12 14 hour days
without feeling some stuff but I do it
for you know three weeks to a month when
prepping for live hacking events and
it's still pretty manageable as long as
I keep my communication up with my
spouse and I um and I you know I I don't
do 60-hour days you know and I still got
a couple hours on either side to chill
and communicate and see touch grass you
know yeah yeah so it sounds like you do
set goals to some extent then but it's
sort of like manageable ones right you
don't want to be like I want to be
number one because then if you yeah
don't hit number one then it's really it
feels bad right yeah goal management I
think is pretty is pretty fuzzy for me
um I definitely do sit down and say all
right you know this is where I'd like my
income goals to be for a year and for a
month and stuff like that and for a live
hacking event I don't set
um I set financial goals for a life
hacking event which is really fun and I
don't know if I mentioned this to you
for Joel but actually Mariah started
helping me figure out this system
um she said hey okay we're gonna set a
goal let's say you know 20 grand or
whatever and uh for every you know tick
above that goal
um you get a prize oh okay and so uh you
know if I do instead of 20 grand Mighty
30 grand then you know I'll get you know
like
I don't know what's a good example one
of one of my one of my prizes this is
the high the highest prize was a hot tub
which I I talk about all the time
because I use it you know all the time
and all my friends just keep their
bathing suits in their car now because
whenever they come over we're hopping
into the hot tub they know it
um uh and that was you know the highest
tier and that's been great and we've
done some work on our house patio and
stuff like that
um and so yeah having those sort of
tiered goals from a financial
perspective is very motivating
um and yeah besides that I'm not really
I don't really set first place second
place third place MBH you know goals
anymore because
um I think those are are largely
variable based off of who else is around
who's hacking how much time they're
putting in and that sort of thing as
well got it
um so
let's see yeah let's talk about taxes
first and then we'll get on more of a
technical side so
um sort of on the business side taxes
Healthcare yeah all that kind of stuff
how do you manage because I think that
most people know bug running income is
not taxed from hacker Warner but crowd
whoever's paying it it's just they just
send you a lump sum money it's kind of
up to you to figure it out so do you
have a like an automated system or any
like system in general that you use to
manage your taxes and all that kind of
financial side of I guess the business
yeah so go ahead and throw out the
preface out there not not tax advice not
legal advice not health insurance advice
boom disclaimed save
um yeah safe very professional
um for taxes I have an LLC which is
structured as an S corp and
um I I kind of do it that way and you
can talk to your accountants about the
way that um that you can do that in in
America it's a pretty common tax
optimization set up
um I pay myself a salary
um through the company and I also issue
um dividends to myself or maybe the
technical term isn't dividends but I
also pull money out as the owner of the
company and then I'm also able to employ
my wife as well
um so uh that's that's a great way to
get value uh from the taxes perspective
and I think to be perfectly honest just
sitting down and paying the big Bill
that it that it takes to get a good
accountant to sit down with you um is
very very worth it for anyone who's
looking to go into a bug Bounty I've
been really impressed with my
accountant's work so definitely
definitely do that yeah I have an
account too I uh yeah he's awesome uh
I'm not gonna say his name because I
want him all to myself but uh but yeah
no find yourself a good accountant ask
some friends for recommendations or
something but um an account is
definitely more it's worth more than
whatever you're gonna pay for it oh yeah
the advice is just Parcels yeah for sure
cool and then from the from the
healthcare perspective I'll just hop on
that really quick
um we are yeah we're at like 57 minutes
right now so
um we gotta we gotta I won't go I won't
talk about this for too long but my blog
post
um I I did do a blog post on hack or
Healthcare
um and it's it's a pretty it's a pretty
good post um sort of outlining my setup
for healthcare uh it talks about how
well I have sort of two areas that I
have two ways that I've solved this
problem in the U.S one is catastrophic
coverage so if I were to like get cancer
or like get hit by a car and break like
30 bones
um how is that getting paid for and for
me that's covered by a health share plan
which you can read about on the on the
blog very affordable I think it's a
hundred and eighty two dollars a month
for me and Mariah or something like that
and then I also the other side of it is
um
the sort of day-to-day care
um which is like you know hey I'm sick I
need a prescription hey I've got a
really bad case of Poison Ivy from
digging around in the weeds in my
backyard help
um maybe that one was a little too too
too clear too specifically triggered
um no uh and you know then for that I
have a DPC subscription which is a
direct Primary Care subscription which
is essentially a contract I've set up
with a doctor that
um you know he I can just text him and
call him and video chat and pretty much
just walk into the office whenever I
feel like it and he's there available to
be to be seen and to answer any
questions and man that is some serious
value you know yeah I think everybody I
know who's self-employed is paying like
five times that at least yeah yeah yeah
it's crazy so I mean it's only one it's
182 for me and Mariah for the
um for the uh
catastrophic care and then the the
subscription every month is like 100
bucks for per person for the doctor so
it's definitely worth it we get out you
know quite cheap with that and we get
really high quality of care so I was
really really grateful to have found a
good solution because Healthcare is so
stressful in the United States that
seems a good way yeah cool okay last
question not on the business side uh how
do you how do you like organize yourself
um you're doing all this hacking you're
hacking like pretty much every day
for many hours a day how do you map out
an application how do you take notes how
do you keep track of different programs
how do you how do you structure it
well um this this really cool friend of
mine named Joel introduced me to vs code
yeah what I what I do is I pop open a vs
code instance and then I spam random
keys and save a file and then I just put
random notes in there on like IDs and
like
weird pieces of JavaScript that I like
or something like that unfortunately I'm
not a terribly organized uh hacker my
um you know I do name my burp tabs I'm
not a lunatic right I do name my burp
tabs but I'm also not taking very
structured notes unfortunately um on the
targets at this point in my progression
as a hacker
um I kind of this is going to sound
really you know uh weird but I just kind
of go with the flow of the application
you know like I'm really just kind of
trying to live in the application and
you know kind of
kind of figure out how it feels
um and and so taking notes taking
structured notes Beyond you know
something that I want to be able to go
back and grab really quick and paste in
um is not something that I that I do
super well um I know a lot of people do
but I don't and um one one tip just on
my methodology that was a total game
changer for me lately was a friend of
mine non-technical friend
um she she showed me lately that you can
Windows has a built-in
clipboard history oh yeah did you know
that I have pulled this up by accident
like so many times it's like Windows
there's a Windows V Windows C or Windows
yes Windows V Windows C is Cortana yeah
Windows V man I love this and then you
can just scroll through and like see a
history so this is my note taking now
like my windows V is my note-taking all
the IDS are in there like all the
sketchy pieces of JavaScript all the
endpoints you know it's all in there
um and I don't know man like I I told
you I it was kind of unsure about
switching to to WSL windows subsystem
for Linux but I do like that one piece
and if I ever go back to Linux I'm
definitely going to find
some sort of similar solution for Linux
yeah okay dude that's awesome
I think we're on time all right yeah
that's a wrap um for the main section um
on full-time Bounty
um I guess tell you what I'll go ahead
and cut the recording here and then
we'll um I'll go ahead and pull Kodi and
Soma on to talk about their bugs and
we'll just splice together that's all
good yeah yeah I'm I'm super pumped for
those who don't know I don't know if we
talked about this but you two people
that you've mentored you're gonna be
bringing on and uh they're gonna be
talking about some bugs that they found
which is super super dope should be
should be really fun um any any closing
thoughts or is that a wrap uh this is
made me think really hard about bug
money full-time and all that kind of
stuff you know um
personal perspective on enjoying the
dark side management and energy
management all that kind of stuff I
think the the closing advice I'll give
is um I think one of the things I've
noticed throughout life is that it's all
about energy management and and finding
the best way to manage your energy is
like the key to everything else so yeah
just finding like what motivates you how
to set those goals and keep it healthy
but also being able to push yourself I
think you do a really awesome job at all
of that and uh I I definitely strive to
be be closer to that thanks man I
appreciate it yeah those those are some
deep thoughts to leave people off with
but definitely definitely uh something
to to be considered and yeah you know
energy is is definitely a um is
definitely a cool thing to optimize for
because I think there's so many people
that optimize for money a lot of people
that optimize for time
um but yeah optimizing for energy is is
definitely definitely something to
consider so yeah with that with that
we'll uh we'll cut it here and we'll
switch over to some bug reports from
kodai and Soma
um yeah awesome thanks for listening
talk to you next week see you sweet
we're rolling what's up guys welcome to
the show hey thank you we've uh we've
got my two my two mentees kodai and Soma
here
um I have the mic shifted further away
from my super loud voice
um closer to them to pick theirs up
um pretty much just gonna have you guys
talk today about the two bugs that we
selected um that you found kind of when
we were working together
um they're pretty great bugs I'm I'm
really proud of them I met these two so
actually let me let me give a disclaimer
before we get into this episode
um
I do not take
mentorship mentee applications I the
last time I mentioned it on air 15
people messaged me and were like hey
anytime you know I only do this for like
friends great guys like these guys that
I know in real life
um so uh I will keep you up to date
about whether that ever changes but for
right now
um no no no mentorship program so
um all right guys you ready to roll
which one of you guys wants to go first
um I can go first all right good I hit
us
um hello everyone my name is kodai I
also go by the name of kodai Choda which
is my my uh silly hacker handle nice
yeah um so Koda is my name and chodai
means like in Japanese like give me give
me something yeah survive um I think you
were the one yeah actually like yeah we
forced him we he couldn't come up with a
name for his hacker one handle so when
we were setting it up we were like all
right it's gonna be kodai chodai which
is a a saying that Mariah came up with
one night when we were doing board game
night or something like that yeah so he
stuck with it forever now because he's
already found some bugs so he's not
gonna ditch that rep I kind of regretted
it yeah well uh so I graduated from
college yeah in March last year and I'm
currently training to be a full-time big
Bounty Hunter yeah
um yeah so I'm at this point where um
I'm not really sure if I'm allowed to
introduce myself as a hacker honestly
yes you are yes you are you're about to
talk about a bug on a podcast absolutely
man so yeah that's about it I guess yeah
are you are you um
I mean do you think you want to focus
primarily on bug Bounty uh from here on
out or you you entertaining employment
options or what uh that's a great
question
um yeah so I'm still kind of sitting on
the fence you know trying to decide uh
which direction yeah I should go to and
the yeah I don't know man but I think at
the end of the day what I really want to
do is
um bug hunting like full time yeah it
gives you that flexibility and yeah yeah
that's good man all right Soma you want
to give a little introduction as well
yeah sure
um I'm Soma I'm doing hacking with my
name of matope
a nickname from Japanese yeah basically
and
I'm still I was a student until February
I just
thank you yeah I just yeah I finished my
bachelor's degree in chemistry and
and computer science I've been working
on my like own mini projects doing some
programming
and that kind of stuff yeah yeah that's
that's great I I remember so some
someone I met through a mutual friend
and he was studying chemistry and I was
like oh that's cool and then we we
talked about it a little bit more and
he's like yeah but look at this cool
like line bot that I wrote and stuff
like that and he had done a bunch of
really cool I.T stuff on the side
um so yeah I was really impressed and
and where are you where are you working
well now that you graduated
yeah from April from next this April I'm
gonna start working for a company called
Rockton which is
a pretty big company in Japan yeah it's
one of the biggest uh you know it's it's
competitor to Amazon in Japan so really
thrilled for you that you nailed that
interview and got that one that's a
really great job
um so yeah I hope you'll continue doing
bug Bounty uh in your free time on the
side and I will definitely will that
sounds good all right so the bugs right
um do you guys need your laptops or are
you just gonna just kind of wing it
all right so uh code I went first doing
intros so maybe Soma wants to go first
doing the bug explanations okay hit us
yeah so I was hacking a Japanese app of
a very famous American company and
I was looking into
strings.xml so this is an Android app
Android app yeah
and then I found this parameter called
kagi which is
um key in Japanese
and they used this parameter to decode
other hard-coded
like really important information
and I think other hackers couldn't find
this because it's you know it's in
Japanese and I was able to find that
because I'm a Japanese
and yeah yeah this is one thing I like
about hacking so you kind of like
utilize many information yeah for
example like HTTP and then web app you
use Linux server languages yeah and then
new natural language too yeah which is
really cool yeah that was such a fun fun
bug we couldn't believe when we saw the
string was like coggy it was literally
just key in Japanese and then it just
decrypted everything that they had
secret in the app so that was really
good find Soma yeah thank you and you
you like um you typically go I guess
you've got more experience with mobile
apps than web application hacking yeah
yeah yeah so that that should definitely
be good for you and I think yeah we've
got some targets we're working on right
now that are are really exciting and not
not uh not mobile actually where you're
focusing on uh another I guess we can't
really say the company name because the
bug isn't even submitted yet but you've
got a another bug in the works yeah yeah
it should be should be really fun it's a
CSS injection yeah CSS injection and
credit card
um post message yeah credit card post
message CSS injection
it's going to be a great bug dude I'm
really excited thank you yeah nice job
man kodai you're up next what you
talking about sure um so I'm going to
talk about this
um numeric idor that me and Justin
actually collaborated on
um so one time
um we were hacking this food delivery
service and when you open up the page
logged in
um
on the
top left hand corner you see this little
pin looking Mark and if you if you
clicked on that it shows a couple of
interesting pieces of user information
and uh such as
drivers driver instructions
um zip code you know the whole address
of the user and stuff and so we thought
okay this is really interesting so we
should you know we so basically we
decided to poke around it a little bit
and
we basically found out that the user uh
no the server on the server side the
server wasn't validating the user
through any secure methodologies but
what the server was actually doing is
that it was validating the user through
this
um 10 digit
value so it was all numeric and so yeah
we
basically
um
and this was in the this was in the
address change functionality right so
yeah you saw those that delivery
instruction zip code the address and
then there was a functionality to change
that in the request that it was it was
sending to the server it was only
validating which users or which address
should be changed via that via that
numeric ID right yeah yeah so it was um
the numeric idea was um at least on the
website called address ID so we decided
to um change the address ID to see
um if the modified malicious user input
that we created will be reflected on the
victims account and we try that on Burke
just modifying the the request body of
uh graphql
post request yeah that's right but uh we
actually didn't see any result on the
request
yeah we're on the HTTP response right so
but we still try to
um
go to the website and see the results
this is really this is really key guys
this is a good this is a good piece here
so to talk talk about that yeah yeah so
we didn't really seat the seat
we didn't see anything
um any
change on the HTTP response but we did
see
the change
the malicious user input reflected on
the victim's page uh yeah that's how we
yeah exactly so what you're saying was
that there was an idor and with
regarding to change the address for a
specific user you could you could
specify a different address for a
different user and uh that that occurred
when you send the request the response
it I mean what was it an error it was an
error right yeah it was 500 error uh
okay so it's a 500 error as a uh a
server error right so it's not a 403
it's not an access denied it's a 500
server error but
it still updated it yep on the victims a
good one man that's a good one so
definitely be on the lookout for that
guys where you um where you're testing
an eye door and even if you get an
access denied or even if you get a you
know 500 server back that doesn't mean
that the attack didn't take effect
um so always validate that your idler
didn't actually take effect
um on the on the victim account and also
check and maybe just use inputs that are
kind of crazy so in this scenario maybe
could I could have changed the address
of
um you know somebody to say you know
yeah this is you know crazy input and
then you know when you're going into
that account if you look at the address
in the future you can say oh wait a
second that actually did take the fact
so those are some great those are some
great tips good stuff guys
um any any takeaways from this you want
to share with the with the crowd
yeah so so from my bug I'd say
I already mentioned a little bit but
you know you can like use a lot of
knowledge for hacking and
um it's not just about vulnerabilities
but
you can use your
um natural language knowledge and also
like cryptography yeah programming yeah
too and
and yeah I learned that from that book
that I found that's awesome yeah so
taking uh areas from taking information
from lots of different areas and
everyone's everyone's a unique hacker
everyone has their own perspective from
which they're hacking
um so that can definitely give you a
unique perspective and help you to find
bugs that other people can't find so
that's a great takeaway could I what
about you
um I had to say
um numeric idors they they're really
super impactful yeah they're very
impactful
um so you should definitely you know
uh
go after that and and you know just like
you said sometimes you don't really see
the results that you would like to see
on the
um https yes the response but definitely
you know maybe like by trying to make it
look a little more
um obvious you can
yeah you should definitely try to see it
on the the victim account the victim
account yeah
um targeting that yeah that makes total
sense
sweet guys thanks for coming on and
sharing I kind of I kind of forced them
into this a little bit
um but yeah I think that's I think
that's it for the episode hope you guys
enjoyed and we'll see you again next
week alright see everybody